<Document>
  # Jellids

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TP14MobJellidPerson" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Jellids are a native species to the planet Trieste resides on. They evolved to survive the deep sea and have trouble surviving on dry land.

  They have a naming scheme based off of stars and constellations, as they had never seen them prior to first contact with Trieste's settlers, and as such have grown to have a strong fascination with space.

  Naming examples: Regulus, Centauri, Sirius, Betelgeuse, Orion

  ## Breathing

  Jellids need to breathe seawater to keep their membrane's osmosis stable, or else they bleed their seawater out and rip their membrane.
  They are, however, immune to the ocean's freezing temperatures and high pressure, making them adept expeditioneers.

  Trieste has developed tubing that can directly feed seawater into their mantle, allowing unobstructed vision.

  ## Power

  Jellids do not eat, nor do they drink. Instead, they have large energy stores that directly convert charged electrons into an energy source.
  They do this by siphoning the electrons from power containing objects such as power cells, stun batons, or disablers.

  If they run out of energy, they will die rapidly. They have an estimated 20 minutes of energy before this happens.

  This also means, however, that they do not take electrical damage normally.
  If shocked, they will instead be stunned as if they had devoured an entire pizza within seconds, alongside this they will get a boost to their energy stores.

  As for pre-Trieste charging, Jellids reportedly used the electricity dense crystals found scattered around the ocean floor.
  While these larger crystals may be dangerous to approach and even risky for Jellids to do so, testing has proved the small shards can be used to power a small flashlight for a limited time.

  ## Electrically Charged

  Jellids, due to their internal energy stores, will burn paper on contact.
  To get around this, Trieste has developed specialized jellidproof gloves for use in writing or reading.
  This helped Jellids with further employment once Trieste and sweetwater were settled in, and more workforce was needed.

  Any Jellids that visit are supplied with their own survival box, as well as the gear necessary for the dryer parts of Trieste.

  ## First contact

  Jellids were first discovered when Trieste settlers first came to the abandoned Sweetwater complex, finding it in disrepair and overrun with algae.
  The first explorers found a native Jellid colony living inside, siphoning the spare energy from the long unpowered SMES and cables.

  They were given universal translators and specialized breathing packs to allow them to enter dry land and join the settlement.
  In exchange, they helped with the renovations of Sweetwater and helped locate The Artifact due to their innate taste for energy.
</Document>
