<Document>
  # Set an example if playing command or security
  All command and security roles are held to higher roleplay standards than other roles. They are expected to have better grasps on the rules, and to be more capable of playing a reasonable character. 
  - Command roles are not learning roles. Members of command must be competent.
  - Security roles are expected to be familiar with the server rules, including Space Law. Enforcement of Space Law is an IC enforcement of many server rules and roleplay standards. 
  - Do not hinder or cause overall negative effects to the platform or its citizens as a member of command or security.
  - Do not abuse your power as command or security.

  ## Why
  Command and Security roles often set the tone for a round. Command members, as leadership roles, are often looked to as guides for players. Command or Security intentionally breaking rules or behaving in silly ways can influence others to do the same. 
  Security's ability to enforce Space Law allows them to cut down on behavior that is not in line with the server roleplay standards. 

  ## Examples
  Acceptable:
  - A member of security accepts a bribe to deliver safe donuts to a prisoner who the Marshal has ordered should only be given donk pockets.
  - An Overseer uses a platform announcement to confess to an embarrassing mistake that they made during the shift.
  - In coordination with the Marshal, an Overseer declares that the platform will recognize the right to bear arms, so all citizens can pick up a disabler at security.
  - The chief medical officer gives a paramedic their portable crew monitor to help them complete their job.
  - A syndicate agent is holding a citizen hostage and threatens to kill them if the Marshal doesn't give them their ID. Seeing no other safe option, the Marshal hands over their ID to the syndicate agent, then begins working to re-secure it and capture the agent as soon as the hostage is safe.
  - Cascade operatives are attacking the platform, so the Overseer and head of personnel both go to the armory and take a weapon.
  - A majority of command votes to demote the Overseer for taking actions harmful to the platform, then the Marshal demotes the Overseer.
  - The Overseer promotes the head of personnel to Overseer.
  - Security releases an antagonist from the brig in exchange for the identities of other traitors.

  Prohibited:
  - A member of security accepts a bribe to ignore a crime or help a prisoner escape.
  - An Overseer sends a ASCII art trollface over platform announcements or as a fax to SolGov.
  - An Overseer declares that all contraband is legal.
  - Command or security allow the use of Syndicate items outside extreme emergencies.
  - The chief medical officer knowingly helps a syndicate agent complete their objectives.
  - A syndicate agent has killed 3 members of security so the Marshal makes them an offer saying that they will space all the weapons in the armory if the syndicate agent stops killing.
  - The Overseer goes to the armory and takes a gun to display in his office without asking anyone, and orders anyone who questions him not to interfere.
  - Members of command decide to demote the Overseer to gain more power for themselves, or in retaliation for a decision that they didn't personally like or agree with, rather than because the decision was actually harmful to the platform.
  - The Overseer promotes a random citizen to Overseer.
  - A member of command gives a random citizen substantial additional access for no reason, unnecessarily, or for a poor reason.
  - A member of command gives a random citizen access to a high security area, like the armory or another member of command's office, for no reason, unnecessarily, or for a poor reason.
  - Security releases an antagonist from the brig in exchange for the antagonist buying them contraband.
</Document>
