<Document>
# Standard Operating Procedure

## Alerts
Different alert levels are in place to briefly state the situation in Trieste. 
This primarily relates to the equipment level expected of Security, as well as advises crew on actions to keep them safe.

Regardless of alert level, citizens are allowed to act in self-defense or the defense of others. Defense must always be done with proportional force to the threat.
Persons being attacked must only do so until the threat is no longer able to attack, and look to escape the threat when possible. Security must be informed as soon as possible.

Examples of proportional force include:
 - Punching when being punched
 - Melee weapons when attacked by melee weapons

In the event of trespassing, theft, or other non-violent crime, non-lethal force may be used against offenders [italic] only if the offender refuses to listen to verbal warning [/italic]

[color=#229c30]Green Alert[/color] is the default alert level of Trieste. There is no present threat to the settlement. Citizens should be working as usual
 - Security is permitted to carry sidearms in the event of emergency
 - Command members may carry flashes for personal defense. 
 - Security requires approval and consent of the target before conducting searches or placing persons under detainment.
 - [color=#ebbc31]Yellow Alert[/color], a structural emergency, follows the same restrictions as Green Alert.

[color=#1e79e8]Blue Alert[/color] is raised when there is evidence of a threat aboard the rig. This is used when a threat is not confirmed, or when it is not major enough to warrant Red Alert.
Citizens should remain on alert, but may perform their duties as usual.
 - Security is permitted to carry sidearms
 - Command members may carry flashes for personal defense
 - Security may conduct searches or place persons into detainment without the consent of the target; Security still requires approval from the Marshal.

[color=#e31b1b]Red Alert[/color] is raised when there is a confirmed, violent, or destructive threat aboard the rig. Citizens should remain sheltered as much as possible and await orders from Command.
 - Security is permitted to carry longarms
 - Command is permitted to carry flashes for personal defense
 - Security may search or place people into detainment without approval first; approval may be given after the search or detainment.
 - [color=#9f4ccf]Code Violet[/color], a severe viral threat, follows the same restriction as Red Alert.

</Document>