<Document>
# Medical SOP 
Due to the importance of emergency medical aid, Medical facilities are expected to abide by the following in order to ensure their department remains orderly and does not violate persons entering as patients.

## Authority of the Chief Medical Officer 
  -  The Chief Medical Officer has the ability to designate all standards and procedures for their medbay. All Medical staff and patients must abide by any standards laid out by the Chief Medical Officer.
  -  The Chief Medical Officer is the highest authority within the medbay. All personnel within the medbay, including non-patients, must listen to all orders given by the Chief Medical Officer. Only the Overseer is exempt from this.

## Do Not Resucitate Orders
 DNRs are orders to halt all efforts to resucitate a persons once they enter cardiac failure. It is recommended that these be filed on paperwork for record keeping and proof. 
 
[color=#a4885c]Personal DNRs:[/color]
 Any person may request to have a DNR approved for themself, if they wish to not be resucitated in the event of an emergency. These requests must be approved by the Chief Medical Officer.
 Command members may request a DNR for themself, but must obtain the approval of the Chief Medical Officer and Overseer. If the CMO is requesting a personal DNR, it must be approved by the Overseer and one other available command member.

[color=#a4885c]Emergency DNRs:[/color] 
 During crises, temporary DNR orders can be issued to individuals whose revival would pose a continual threat to the crew. This includes any parties whom raid the settlement, pose significant armed threat to the settlement, or whose goals would mean mass destruction of the settlement or loss of life.
 These orders are issued so as to leave medical crew available to focus on the revival of citizens of the settlement, and to prevent hostile parties from continuing to threaten the settlement. 
 Citzens commiting violent, even capital crimes, is not enough to warrant issuing an emergency DNR. This provision exists only to allow breathing room for medical or security during crises where their attention is needed elswhere. 
 Once the crisis is over, the Emergency DNR is to be assumed as invalid and resucitation must be attempted to the best of the ability of available medical staff.

## Do Not Borg Orders
DNBs are orders to not place a person's brain into an MMI and/or use the MMI to control a cyborg unit if they should enter brain death and be unrevivable by usual means. It is recommended that these be filed on paperwork for record keeping and proof.

Any person may request to have a DNB approved for themself, if they wish to not be used in a borg chassis or MMI after death. DNBs must obtain the approval of the Chief Medical Officer. 
Members of Command may request to have a DNB approved for themself, but must obtain approval by the Chief Medical Officer. If the Chief Medical Officer wishes to file a DNB, it must be approved by the Overseer. Command members should notify the Overseer once they have an approved DNB. 

Persons with a DNB must have their bodies stored within the morgue. These should then be brought aboard transit to the nearest SolGov facility for cloning, if the person wished. 

## Do Not Clone Orders
DNCs are orders to not use cloning machines to create a genetic clone of a person after their death. It is recommended that these be filed on paperwork for record keeping and proof. 

Any person may request to have a DNC filed for themselves, if they wish to not be cloned into a new body after death. They must obtain approval by the Chief Medical Officer.
Members of Command may request to have a DNC filed for themselves, and must obtain approval from the Chief Medical Officer. If the Chief Medical Officer requests a personal DNC, they must obtain approval from the Overseer. Command members should notify the Overseer once they have an approved DNC.

Persons with a DNC do not need to be transferred to SolGov facilities aboard transport shuttles. They may instead remain in the local morgue until their proper funeral and/or burial. 
</Document>