<Document>
 # Rights of Prisoners
  Prisoners still have certain rights that must be upheld by law enforcement:
  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to basic communications equipment (Radios) so long as they are not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners with a 15 minute or longer sentence must be granted a chance to appeal their charges. See: Appeals.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation or appeal, if requested and available.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA after confinement has finished, unless there is solid proof of PDA tampering. In case of tampering, the PDA is to be secured and replaced with a new unit.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement, and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life and limb.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to the brig general population room for the duration of their sentence. This right may be revoked at the discretion of the Marshal or Warden if a prisoner is deemed a threat to other prisoners, officers, or the brig structure.

 ## Appeals
  Prisoners additionally have the right to an appeal if they believe the charges to be more extreme than fitting their actions, or if they believe that Security have failed to assign a fitting charge. They must inform Security that they wish to appeal as soon as possible.
  Appeals are used to reduce sentences and amend incorrect charges. They may not add additional charges or brig time, nor pardon prisoners of crimes fitting their actions.
  Prisoners must have their brig timer started while they wait for an appeal.
  
  [color=#a4885c]Handling an Appeal:[/color]
  Appeals are made out to a designated handler, who is always an uninvolved party to the crime and not a witness. Appeals may first be handled by the Marshal or Overseer; if neither area available they may be handled by the Warden. If any of these are currently occupied and can not come to the Brig, they may defer the appeal. Ideally it is deferred to the next available of the three listed prior. When all are occupied or involved in the arrest, then it may be deferred to an uninvolved member of Security.
  Appeals may be addressed to SolGov, regardless of if an appeal with prior persons has begun. Any decision made in a response by SolGov is final. If no response is received within 10 minutes the appeal is considered denied.
  Prisoners have a right to a lawyer during the appeal process, if one is available. 

  The appeal processor must meet with the prisoner, and the appeal must be handled in person unless adressed to SolGov. The charges are listed one by one, by either the handler or any Security Officer. Discussion of witness accounts, story of accused, and evidence is recommended.
  The handler then decides an outcome for each charge, listing their decisions for each charge. The appeal handler may:
  - Decide the charges are valid, no modification
  - Modify the charge to a lower charge
  - Reduce the sentenced time, without modifying the charge
  - Remove charges the prisoner is found innocent for
  The prisoner then serves the remaining punishment after any modification. 

  [color=#a4885c]Suspending Appeals:[/color]
  The appeal process may be suspended or postponed during any of the following situations:
  - Threats requiring evacuation
  - Hostile presence aboard the rig
  - Riots or jailbreaks
  - The prisoner requires medical aid and is unconscious
  - There is already an appeal being processed
  - The prisoner has escaped or is unreachable in person

 ## Parole
  Prisoners sentenced to permanent confinement are eligble to be let out on parole at the discretion of the Marshal or Warden. Prisoners must not have commited additional crimes within the brig in order to remain eligible. 
  Prisoners who wish to be let out on parole must request to meet with either the Marshal or Warden. They have a right to allow a lawyer to attend the meeting, if one is available. 
  If the Marshal or Warden agree to the parole, the prisoner is allowed to exit the brig under as many conditions as the Marshal or Warden deem necessary, so long as the conditions do not inflict harm upon the prisoner.

  [color=#a4885c]Parole Officers:[/color]
  Once a parole is agreed upon, a Parole Officer (PO) must be appointed for the paroled prisoner. Any member of security may be appointed as a PO. 
  The PO is responsible for ensuring that the conditions of the parole are not violated by the prisoner. This also includes the responsibility of using the remote for any shockpacks that the prisoner may be required to wear. The PO is also responsible for ensuring the safety and health of the prisoner during their parole. 
</Document>