<Document>
  # Search and Seizure

  Security may conduct searches of any person or department should it be deemed necessary. Searches can only be performed once approved by either the Marshal or Overseer. If the Marshal personally requests a warrant, it must be approved by the Overseer. Obtaining a written, stamped warrant is recommended.
  If the rig is in blue alert or above, searches may be conducted without a warrant.

  ## Personnel
   - Security must inform the suspect of why they are being searched. The search should be conducted either in the brig or in an isolated area. If the suspect does not comply, non-lethals and restraints may be applied. 
   - Officers may check any pouch, belt, back, or other storage item on a person. If any contraband is found, it must be secured until the search is complete. If the contraband warrants arrest, then Officers may arrest the suspect.
   - Otherwise, release the suspect and take contraband back to the brig.

  ## Departments
   - Inform the department that a search will be conducted. Any persons who are not part of the department should be escorted out. If anyone responsible for the department is available, inform them of the reason for the search.
   - If no one with access to the department is available, then forceful overriding of the doors is permitted. 
   - Once access is available, search the whole department thoroughly. Any contraband must be secured.
   - When completed, restore any overrides or damage done, bring contraband to the brig, and reopen the department.

  ## Confiscated Contraband
  Officers may not be permitted to use any items, chemicals, or weapons confiscated during searches. This restriction may only be lifted if extreme, hostile force is present on the rig and the use of such items are deemed beneficial.
  Otherwise, all contraband confiscated by Officers is considered evidence and must be stored in either an evidence locker or the armory.  

  ## Investigative Detainment 
   Officers may request a suspect to be brought under investigative detainment, if they wish to find solid evidence of wrongdoing. Suspects may only be detained after recieving an approval and warrant by the Marshal. 
   Detainees have a right to request that a lawyer be present during their detainment. Detainees may not be held for longer than 5 minutes; after this time they must be released.

   While a suspect is under Investigative Detainment officers may:
   - Interview the detainee, or any persons affiliated with them who are not detained.
   - Conduct a search of the detainee and their belongings.

  If evidence of wrongdoing is found, then the detainee is to be charged and processed as a prisoner. The time spent in detention must be subtracted from their total sentence.
  If insufficient evidence is found, then the detainee must be released.
  </Document>